Guide to the Arthur H. and Mary Marden Dean Lafayette Collection, 1520-1973
Lafayette Collection (Arthur H. and Mary Marden Dean Lafayette Collection), 1520-1973
- Series III. Correspondence
  - B. Incoming
    - [Gasbonder, C. and Borngoing, Caglus?] (Box 58, Folder 47)
      Monsieur le Deputé/Il n'y a que la licence...
    - Gaspari, Luigi (Box 58, Folder 48)
      12 Luglio 1827, Hampton Sydney (Virginia) 1l.
    - [Geneste, L.] (Box 58, Folder 49)
      AL (frag.) to [Adrienne de Noailles, marquise de Lafayette]
      ...Vu coup de fortune auquel je ne m'attendrai pas...
    - Geneste, L. (Box 58, Folder 50)
      ALS to [Adrienne de Noailles, marquise de Lafayette]
      23 Octobre 1790, 4 leaves.
    - Geneste, L. (Box 59, Folder 1)
      ALS (copy) to Messieurs les administrateurs de Cayenne
    - Geneste, L. (Box 59, Folder 2)
      ALS (copy) to M. Bourgon
    - Geneste, L. (Box 59, Folder 3)
      ALS to [Adrienne de Noailles Marquise de Lafayette]
      18 Mars 1791, 2 ll.
    - Geneste, L. (Box 59, Folder 4)
      6 Juin 1791, 4 leaves.
    - Geneste, L. (Box 59, Folder 5)
      14 Octobre 1791, 2 ll.
    - Geneste, L. (Box 59, Folder 6)
      ALS to M. de Foncin
      26 Octobre 1791, Cayenne. 1l.
    - Geneste, L. (Box 59, Folder 7)
      22 Janvier 1792, 6 leaves.
    - Geneste, L. (Box 59, Folder 8)
      ALS to Adrienne de Noailles Marquise de Lafayette]
      4 Avril 1792, 4 leaves.
    - Geneste, L. (Box 59, Folder 9)
      10 Mai 1792, 1l.
    - Geneva, [N.Y.] ? (Box 59, Folder 10)
      [n. d.] Geneva, 1l.
      The citizens of Geneva are sensible that...
    - [Gentit St. Antoine, Cte.?] (Box 59, Folder 11)
      11 Mars 1819, Paris. 1l.
    - Geoffroy St. Hilaire, Etienne, 1772-1844 (Box 59, Folder 12)
      ALS to Joseph Lakanal
      10 Juin 1823, Paris. 1l.
    - Gérard, Maurice Etienne, Comte, 1773-1855 (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Gérard, Maurice Etienne, Comte, 1773-1855 (Box 59, Folder 14)
      29 Septembre 1830, 1l.
    - Geyelle [?], Comte de (Box 59, Folder 15)
      11 Juin 1828, 1l.
    - Ghersi, F. & [Giovan Batista?] (Box 59, Folder 16)
      20 Mars 1831, Macon. 1l.
    - Giberlin, E. A. (Box 59, Folder 17)
      ALS to Mme. de Tessé
      8 Prairial an 9 [28 Mai 1801] Versailles, 1l.
    - Gil, Andres (Box 59, Folder 18)
      ALS to M. le Général Lafayette
      10 May 1827, 1l.
    - Giles, William Branch, 1762-1830 (Box 59, Folder 19)
      May 15, 1828. Richmond, 1l.
    - Giorgi Bertolo, Comte de (Box 59, Folder 20)
      ALS to Monsieur le General Lafayette
      Le 23 - 1833, Bruxelles. 1l.
      Mon Général/Exilé par la quatrième fois de France...
    - Girardin, Ernest Stanislas, Marquis de, 1802 -1874 (Box 59, Folder 21)
      13 Juin 1837 [n.p.] 1l.
    - [?] (Box 59, Folder 22)
      ALS to [La Marquise de Vienne?]
      9 Septembre 1782, Artois. 1l.
    - Giunta Liberatrice Italiana (Box 59, Folder 23)
      7 Avril 1831, Paris. 1l.
    - Godard, traiteur (Box 59, Folder 24)
      18 xbre 1834, Paris. 1l.
    - Godefroy (Box 59, Folder 25)
      ALS to M. de Tessé
      11 Janvier 1810 [Brionne?] 1l.
    - Goff, William B. (Box 59, Folder 26)
      ALS to General de Lafayette
      November 2nd 1829, 1l.
    - Gonon (Box 59, Folder 27)
      29 Septembre 1825, 2 ll.
    - Gory, A. (Box 59, Folder 28)
      Will you pardon this second intrusion...
    - Gouvion St. Cyr, Laurent, Ministre de la Guerre, 1764-1830 (Box 59, Folder 29)
      22 Février 1819, Paris. 1l.
    - Graham, George (Box 59, Folder 30)
      June 10th 1825, 1l.
    - Grammont (Box 59, Folder 31)
      ALS Duplicata--à Monsieur George de Lafayette
      6 Juillet 1824, Paris. 1l.
    - Grammont, Ferdinand de, 1805-1889 (Box 59, Folder 32)
      3 Avril 1847, Paris. 1l.
    - Grammont, Madame de (Box 59, Folder 33)
      ALS to Madame de Chavaniac
      27 Floréal [c. 16 Mai] [n.y.] 1l.
      Vous connaisses asses mon coeur...
    - Grammont, V. de (Box 59, Folder 34)
      ALS to Emilie (de Tracy) de Lafayette
      12 Août 1849, Villersexel. 1l.
    - Grant, James (Box 59, Folder 35)
    - Grasse, Admiral de (Box 59, Folder 36)
      ALS (copy) to M. le Marquis de Lafayette
      30 Août 1781, 1l.
    - Grasse, Comte Alexandre de (Box 59, Folder 37)
      23 Octobre 1830, 2 ll.
    - Grasse, Comte Alexandrede (Box 59, Folder 38)
      19 Novembre 1830, 3 ll.
    - Gray, Francis Calley, 1790-1856 (Box 59, Folder 39)
      21 Septembre, Tuesday. No. 4 Place Vendôme. 1l.
    - Greene, Nathaneal, 1742-1786 (Box 59, Folder 40)
      March 22, 1781. 1l.
    - Greene, Nathaneal, 1742-1786 (Box 59, Folder 41)
      November 9, 1783. Philadelphia. 1l.
    - Greenonugh, Horatio, 1805-1852 (Box 59, Folder 42)
      August 19, 1834. Paris. 1l.
    - Gregory (Box 59, Folder 43)
      20 Aôut 1830, 4 ll.
    - Grene, Mitchel (Box 59, Folder 44)
      August 15th 1830, 1l.
    - Griffin, (Mme.) Constance Baton (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Griffits, Samuel P. (Box 60, Folder 2)
      23rd 1825, 7 mo. 1l.
    - Grosjean, (Mme.) Marthe Gonon (Box 60, Folder 3)
      ALS to Monsieur Lafayette
      19 Mai 1837, 1l.
    - Grouchy, Emmanuel, marquis de (Box 60, Folder 4)
      Maréchal de France, 1766-1847
      ALS to [Madame G.W. Lafayette?]
      18 May 1807, Strasbourg. 1l.
    - Grouchy, Emmanuel, marquis de (Box 60, Folder 5)
      25 Avril 1815, New York. 1l.
    - Grouchy, Emmanuel, marquis de (Box 60, Folder 6)
      1 Août 1816, Philadelphie. 1l.
    - Grouchy, Emmanuel, marquis de (Box 60, Folder 7)
      19 Juillet 1817, Philadelphie. 1l.
    - Grubb, Hannah (Box 60, Folder 8)
      August 16th 1830, London. 3 ll.
    - Grubb, Hannah (Box 60, Folder 9)
      September 6, 1830. London. 2 ll.
    - Grubb, Hannah (Box 60, Folder 10)
      December 31, 1830. 1l.
    - Guda, Bazilio (Box 60, Folder 11)
      26 Febbraio 1830, Venizza. 1l.
    - Guibert, B. (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Guichard, Charles (Box 60, Folder 13)
      8 Février 1825, 2 ll.
    - Guichard, Charles (Box 60, Folder 14)
      17 Octobre 1825, 1l.
    - Guichard, Charles (Box 60, Folder 15)
      27 Décembre 1825, 1l.
    - Guichard, Charles (Box 60, Folder 16)
      24 Août 1827, 1l.
    - Guillaume, M. (Box 60, Folder 17)
      ALS to Mme. Beauchet
      24 Prairial an 9 [13 Juin 1801] Metz, 1l.
    - Guillet, Isidore (Box 60, Folder 18)
      26 Octobre 1828, 1l.
    - Guizot, François Pierre Guillaume, 1787-1874 (Box 60, Folder 19a)
      22 Août 1829, 2 ll.
    - Gurley, Ralph Randolph, on behalf of the Colonization Society (Box 60, Folder 19b)
      23 July 1831
    - Gurley, Ralph Randolph, on behalf of the Colonization Society (Box 60, Folder 19c)
      4 September 1832, 2 ll.
    - Guyot-[Delignières] (Box 60, Folder 20)
      17 Décembre 1828, 1l.
    - Guyot-Delignières (Box 60, Folder 21)
      7 Janvier 1829, 1l.
    - Hackett, Ann (Box 60, Folder 22)
      July 7, 1825. Jamaica. 2 ll. + 1
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 23)
      23 April 1834, New York. 1l.
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 24)
      15th June 1834, New York. 1l.
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 25)
      30th June 1834, New York. 1l.
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 26)
      1 July 1834, New York. 1l.
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 27)
      15 November 1834, Mobile. 1l.
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 28)
      Novembre 4, 1835. Paris, 1l.
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 29)
      16th September 1837, Paris. 1l.
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 30)
      21 September 1837, Paris. 1l.
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 31)
      29th December 1838, New Orleans. 1l.
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 32)
      30th December 1838, New Orleans. 1l.
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 33)
      31 August 1839, Paris. 1l.
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 34)
      L [copy, frag.] to [George Washington Lafayette]
      3 Juin 1840 [n.p.]
      Johnson, Sidney L.
      L [copy, frag.] to Virginie (de Lafayette) de Lasteyrie
      21 Septembre 1841, Tours. 1l.
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 35)
      June 3rd 1840, New Orleans. 1l.
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 36)
      9 August 1841, New Orleans. 1l.
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 37)
      September 5th 1844, London. 1l.
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 38)
      November 24, 1848. New Orleans. 2 ll.
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 39)
      22 March 1850, Paris. 1l.
      Dear Sir/My agent at New Orleans...
    - Hagan, John (Box 60, Folder 40)
      1st May 1850, Paris. 1l.
      Dear Sir/I have a letter...
    - Hagarty, James (Box 60, Folder 41)
      18 August 1830, Liverpool. 2 ll.
    - Haiti (Box 60, Folder 42)
      3 Décembre [n.y.] 2 ll.
    - Haley (Box 60, Folder 43)
      12th August 1830, Nantes. 1l.
    - Hallam, Arthur Henry, 1811-1833 (Box 60, Folder 44)
      August 8, 1830. Montpellier. 1l.
    - Hamden, Aga (Box 60, Folder 45)
      14 Mai 1833, Marseille. [PM] 1l.
    - Hamilton, Alexander (Box 60, Folder 46)
      January 11th 1830, 1l.
    - Hamilton, Alexander (Box 60, Folder 47)
      9th August 1830, Edinburgh. 1l.
    - Hamilton, LaRoche (Box 60, Folder 48)
      2d Août 1830, Brussels. 1l.
    - Hamilton, LaRoche (Box 60, Folder 49)
      4 d'Août 1830, Bruxelles. 1l.
    - Hamilton, La Roche (Box 61, Folder 1)
      12 Août 1830, Bruxelles. 2 ll.
    - Harkness, Edson (Box 61, Folder 2)
      28 June 1833, 1l.
    - Harrison, William Henry, 1773-1841 (Box 61, Folder 3)
      9th August 1825, Cincinnati. 1l.
    - Harrison, William Henry, 1773-1841 (Box 61, Folder 4)
      5th May 1829, Bogota. 1l.
    - Hartford, Connecticut (Box 61, Folder 5)
      [n.d., 1824-1825] Hartford, Conn. 1l.
    - Hazelwood School (Box 61, Folder 6)
      ALS [signed R.H. Williamson, Jr.] to Lafayette
      August 23rd 1830, Hazelwood. 1l.
    - Hedouïn (Box 61, Folder 7)
      ALS to M. Dubourg
      14 Octobre [n.y.] 1l.
    - [Hedouïn] (Box 61, Folder 8)
      AL to M. Dubourg
      15 Octobre 1768, Ham. 1l.
    - Heine, Carlos (Box 61, Folder 9)
      24 Mars 1829, 1l.
    - Henster, C.A. (Box 61, Folder 10)
      Settlement Blackhaus, Tioga County Liberty Post Offifce. 1l.
    - Herrera, Prospero (Box 61, Folder 11)
      30 Juin 1833, 2 ll.
    - Hervé, F. (Box 61, Folder 12)
      August 9th 1830 [Paris] 1l.
    - Heutz (Box 61, Folder 13)
      AL to General [Thionville]
      [n.d., n.p.] 4 ll.
      Mon Général/M. de Bouillé ayant fait demander à Nostre Comité un Certificat de service...
    - [Heutz] (Box 61, Folder 14)
      AL to [Thionville]
      [n.d.,n.p.] 5 ll.
      Mon Général/un Directeur de Luxembourg a dit
      en passant ici...
    - Heutz (Box 61, Folder 15)
      26 8bre (Octobre) [1789] 8 ll.
      Mon Général/Nous sommes toujours ici entre la
      crainte et l'espérance...
    - Heutz (Box 61, Folder 16)
      ALS to Thionville
      Attestation relative ? aux Detachements de la Chaine...
      2 9bre [Novembre] 1789, 6 ll.
    - Heutz (Box 61, Folder 17)
      9 9bre [Novembre] 1789 [n.p.] 11 leaves
      Mon Général/Depuis ma derniere en datte du 2 Courant...
    - Hill, Richard (Box 61, Folder 18)
      ALS to Dr. Philip
      March 13th 1829, London. 3 ll.
    - Hoane, Joseph Wallis (Box 61, Folder 19)
      May 30th 1826, Paris. 1l.
    - Hoane, Joseph Wallis (Box 61, Folder 20)
      July 29, 1826. Paris. 1l.
    - Hoane, Joseph Wallis (Box 61, Folder 21)
      November 4, 1826. Paris. 1l.
    - Hodges, G. Lloyd (Box 61, Folder 22)
      30th December 1832, London. 1l.
    - Hodges, G. Lloyd (Box 61, Folder 23)
      29th March 1833, London. 1l.
    - Holdredge, Sarah L. (Box 61, Folder 24)
      October 24th 1830, Nantes. 1l.
    - Holland, Henry Richard Vassall-Fox, 1773-1840 (Box 61, Folder 25)
    - Holland, Henry Richard Vassall-Fox, 1773-1840 (Box 61, Folder 26)
    - Holland, Henry Richard Vassall-Fox, 1773-1840 (Box 61, Folder 27)
      November 9 [n.y.] 1l.
    - Holland, Henry Richard Vassall-Fox, 1773-1840 (Box 61, Folder 28)
      April 14, 1814. Holland House, 1l.
    - Holland, Henry Richard Vassall-Fox, 1773-1840 (Box 61, Folder 29)
      7th April 1818, Holland House. 2 ll.
    - Holland, Henry Richard Vassall-Fox, 1773-1840 (Box 61, Folder 30)
      17th June 1819, 1l.
    - Holland, Henry Richard Vassall-Fox, 1773-1840 (Box 61, Folder 31)
      18 August 1830, Holland House. 2 ll.
    - Holland, Henry Richard Vassall-Fox, 1773-1840 (Box 61, Folder 32)
      6 February 1831, Old Burlington Street. London, 2 ll.
    - Holland, Henry Richard Vassall-Fox, 1773-1840 (Box 61, Folder 33)
      ALS to G.W. Lafayette
      21 February 1834, London. 1l.
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 34)
      May 6, 1826. New York, 1l.
      I pray you to accept...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 35)
      July 27th 1826, New York. 1l.
      According to promise...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 36)
      November 22d 1826, New York. 1l.
      I received your kind letter...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 37)
      May 5th 1827, New York. 1l.
      Deprived as I am...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 38)
      This will be handed...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 39)
      July 23rd 1827, New York. 1l.
      Fearing that you might...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 40)
      October 15th 1827, New York. 1l.
      I avail myself of the occasion...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 41)
      November 22, 1827. New York, 1l.
      I ask your kind attentions...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 42)
      April 30, 1828. New York, 1l.
      I heard with deep distress...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 43)
      May 30th 1828, New York. 1l.
      I avail myself...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 44)
      I recommend to your kind heart...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 45)
      October 19th 1829, New York. 1l.
      By the time this letter...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 46)
      April 14th 1830, New York. 1l.
      I have been a long time...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 47)
      May 7th 1830, New York. 1l.
      The pain of parting...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 48)
      July 31, 1830. New York,1 l.
      Count Ney, who has done...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 49)
      September 22nd 1830, New York. 1l.
      This letter will, I trust...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 50)
      September 28th 1830. New York, 1l.
      I ask your kind notice...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 51)
      September 28th 1830, New York. 1l.
      I thank you...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 52)
      November 30th 1830, New York. 1l.
      I have been actively engaged...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 53)
      December 9th 1830, New York. 1l.
      Amongst other agreeable duties...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 61, Folder 54)
      This letter will be presented...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 62, Folder 1)
      January 6th 1831, New York. 1l.
      I received your letter...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 62, Folder 2)
      February 7th 1831, New York. 1l.
      Mr. Ball Hughes...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 62, Folder 3)
      April 20th 1832, New York. 1l.
      I have a moment...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 62, Folder 4)
      July 2nd 1832, New York. 1l.
      Mr. Frederick G. Foster...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 62, Folder 5)
      May 6th 1833, New York. 1l.
      It is now a long time...
    - Hone, Philip (Box 62, Folder 6)
      Two Gentlemen of High...
    - Huber and Van Hoey (Box 62, Folder 7)
      14 Mars 1790, Paris. 1l.
    - Huger, Francis Kinloch, 1773-1855 (Box 62, Folder 8)
      21st May 1822, Hills of [Santee?] 1l.
    - Huger, Francis Kincloch, 1773-1855 (Box 62, Folder 9)
      7th June 1825, Pendleton. 1l.
    - Huger, Francis Kincloch, 1773-1855 (Box 62, Folder 10)
      2nd October 1826. Pendleton, S.C. 1l.
    - Huger, Francis Kincloch, 1773-1855 (Box 62, Folder 11)
      20th April 1830. Pendleton, S.C. 1l.
    - Huger, Francis Kincloch, 1773-1855 (Box 62, Folder 12)
      24th July 1831. Pendleton, S.C. 1l.
    - Hughes, Christopher (Box 62, Folder 13)
      October 1st 1818, Stockholm. 2 ll.
    - Hughes, Christopher (Box 62, Folder 14)
      November 10, 1828. Brussels, 1l.
    - Hughes, Christopher (Box 62, Folder 15)
      March 21, 1830. Brussels. 1l.
    - Hughes, Christopher (Box 62, Folder 16)
      24 August 1830, Stockholm. 2 ll.
    - Hughes, Christopher (Box 62, Folder 17)
      11 October 1831, Stockhom. 1l.
    - Hughes, Dorothy (Box 62, Folder 18)
      October 5, 1830. 1l.
    - "Humanitus" (Box 62, Folder 19)
      8th Month [August] 21, 1830. Liverpool, 1l.
    - Humboldt, [Alexandre] (Box 62, Folder 20)
      Ce mardi [October 1818, n.p.], 1l.
    - Hume, Joseph, 1777-1855 (Box 62, Folder 21)
    - Hume, Joseph, 1777-1855 (Box 62, Folder 22)
      29th March 1828, London. 1l.
    - Hume, Joseph, 1777-1855 (Box 62, Folder 23)
      10 June 1828, London. 1l.
    - Hume, Joseph, 1777-1855 (Box 62, Folder 24)
      11 June 1828, London. 1l.
    - Hume, Joseph, 177-1855 (Box 62, Folder 25)
      December 8, 1828 [London] 1l.
    - Hume, Joseph, 1777-1855 (Box 62, Folder 26)
      ALS to W. B. Lawrence, Esq.
      9 December 1828, London. 1l.
    - Hume, Joseph, 1777-1855 (Box 62, Folder 27)
      L [aman.] to Lafayette
      18 April 1829, London. 1l.
      & accompanying document.
    - Hume, Joseph, 1777-1855 (Box 62, Folder 28)
      16th July 1829, London. 1l.
    - Hume, Joseph, 1777-1855 (Box 62, Folder 29)
      9th February 1830 [London] 1l.
    - Hume, Joseph, 1777-1855 (Box 62, Folder 30)
      August 28th 1830, Abroath in North Britain. 1l.
    - Hume, Joseph, 1777-1855 (Box 62, Folder 31)
      1st December 1830, London. 1l.
    - Hume, Joseph, 1777-1825 (Box 62, Folder 32)
      ALS to the prefet of the Municicpality of Paris
      1 January 1831, London. 1l.
    - Hume, Joseph, 1777-1855 (Box 62, Folder 33)
      12 January 1831 [London] 1l.
    - Hume, Joseph, 1777-1855 (Box 62, Folder 34)
      18th November 1833, Paris. 1l.
    - Hunt, Henry, 1773-1835 (Box 62, Folder 35)
      September 15th 1831, London. 1l.
    - Hutchinson (Box 62, Folder 36)
    - Hutchinson, J.P. (Box 62, Folder 37)
      24 October 1831, Monday. [Paris] 1l.
    - Hyde, Robert B. (Box 62, Folder 38)
      June 5th 1825. Buffalo, 1l.
    - Hynes, P.S. (Box 62, Folder 39)
      November 15th 1830, Paris. 1l.
    - Imbert, Jean C. (Box 62, Folder 40)
      1er Février 1822, 2 ll.
    - Ipswich, Mass. (Box 62, Folder 41)
      May 30th 1825. Ipswich, Mass. 1l.
    - Ireton, John (Box 62, Folder 42)
      August 28, 1830. Cork, 1l.
    - Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845 (Box 62, Folder 43)
      October 14th 1821, Washington City. 1l.
    - Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845 (Box 62, Folder 44)
      October 8th 1829, Washington. 1l.
    - Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845 (Box 62, Folder 45)
      September 28th 1830, Washington. 1l.
    - Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845 (Box 62, Folder 46)
      October 1st 1830, Washington. 1l.
    - Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845 (Box 62, Folder 47)
      December 23rd 1830 [n.p.] 1l.
    - Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845 (Box 62, Folder 48)
      January 19th 1831, Washington. 1l.
      My dear General, an extract from a letter...
    - Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845 (Box 62, Folder 49)
      5th June 1833, Washington City. 1l.
    - Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845 (Box 63, Folder 1)
      21 September 1833, Washington City. 1l.
    - Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845 (Box 63, Folder 2)
      September 28th 1833, Washington. 1l.
    - Jackson, Henry (Box 63, Folder 3)
      30 June 1816, 2 ll.
    - Jacob, Antoine (Box 63, Folder 4)
      16 Avril 1836, Vienne. 1l.
      Monsieur!/N'ayant pas encore reçu quelque...
    - Jacobelli, Prospero (Box 63, Folder 5)
      29 Gennaio 1833, Antibbo. 1l.
    - Jacquemin, Miolas (Box 63, Folder 6)
      ALS to [Monsieur Dutrague?]
      Monsieur/Antoine Sevère le couturier votre fils
      porteur de la présente venait souvent me voir...
    - Jacquemin, Miolas (Box 63, Folder 7)
      La réputation que vous vous êtes faite...
    - Jacquemin, Miolas (Box 63, Folder 8)
      ALS (copy) to Monsigneur le Comte de la Luzerne
    - Jacquemin, Miolas (Box 63, Folder 9)
      ALS (copy)
      Copie du mémoire que l'abbé Jacquemin préfet...
    - Jacquemin, Miolas (Box 63, Folder 10)
      ALS (copy) to [Adrienne de Noailles marquise de Lafayette]
    - Jacquemin, Miolas (Box 63, Folder 11)
      18 Décembre 1789, 1l.
    - Jacquemin, Miolas (Box 63, Folder 12)
      20 Février 1790, 1l.
      Nos seigneurs les représentants de la nation française...
    - Jacquemin, Miolas (Box 63, Folder 13)
      5 Octobre 1790, 1l.
    - Jarvis, Samuel Farmar (Box 63, Folder 14)
      August 20th 1830, Leghorn. 1l.
    - Jefferson, Thomas, Pres. U.S. 1743-1826 (Box 63, Folder 15)
      A [aman.] L (copy) to M [Georges Washington] de Lafayette
      [n.d.] Monticello, 1l.
      Dear Sir/The inquiries of Congress were the first intimation...
    - Jefferson, Thomas, Pres. U.S., 1743-1826 (Box 63, Folder 16)
      March 13, 1801. Washington, 1l.
      My dear Friend/I received a letter from you the last year...
    - Jefferson, Thomas, Pres. U.S., 1743-1826 (Box 63, Folder 17)
      November 4 1803, Washington. 1l.
      I have received several letters from you...
    - Jefferson, Thomas, Pres. U.S., 1743-1826 (Box 63, Folder 18)
      March 30, 1804. Washington, 1l.
      I formerly, my dear friend, mentioned to you my wish...
    - Jefferson, Thomas, Pres. U.S., 1743-1826 (Box 63, Folder 19)
      June 27, [18]04 Washington, 1l.
      On the 30th of March I informed you...
    - Jefferson, Thomas, Pres. U.S., 1743-1826 (Box 63, Folder 20)
      ALS (triplicate) to Madame de Tessé
      October 26, [18]05, Washinton. 2 ll.
      Dear Madam,/The blockade of Havre still continuing...
    - Jefferson, Thomas, Pres. U.S., 1743-1826 (Box 63, Folder 21)
      ALS (Duplicate) to Madame de Tessé
      February 21, [18]07. Washington, 1l.
      My dear Madam/On the 26th of October 1805 I had...
    - Jefferson, Thomas, Pres. U.S., 1743-1826 (Box 63, Folder 22)
      July 14 [18]07, Washington. 1l.
      My dear Friend/I received last night your letters...
    - Jefferson, Thomas, Pres. U.S., 1743-1826 (Box 63, Folder 23)
      April 28 [18]08, Washington. 1l.
      My dear Sir/I wrote you last on the 14th of July...
    - Jefferson, Thomas, Pres. U.S., 1743-1826 (Box 63, Folder 24)
      July 15 [18]08, Washington. 1l.
      My dear friend/I have received by the Orage your...
    - Jennings, H.C. (Box 63, Folder 25)
      10 August 1830 [Paris] 1l.
    - Johnson, Henry, 1783-1864 (Box 63, Folder 26)
      April 14th 1827, New Orleans. 1l.
    - Johnson, M. (Box 63, Folder 27)
      August 26th 1830, 1l.
    - Johnson, Sidney L. (Box 63, Folder 28)
      ALS to Madame de Lasteyrie
      21 Septembre 1841, Paris. 1l.
    - Jones. (Box 63, Folder 29)
      ALS to Warren Miller Jones [his son]
      September 6th 1830, London. 1l.
    - Jones, Colonel (Box 63, Folder 30)
      September 7, 1830. London, 1l.
      & printed broadside
    - Jones, L.J. (Box 63, Folder 31)
      ALS to MacNally
    - Jorre, J.A. (Box 63, Folder 32)
      August 18th 1830, La Sauserie near Elbeauf. 2 ll.
    - Jossolt (Box 63, Folder 33)
      17 Août 1830, 5 ll.
    - Joubert (Box 63, Folder 34)
      [1830] 1l.
      Le général Lafayette ne...
    - Joy, G. (Box 63, Folder 35)
      22 February 1825. London, 1l.
    - Joy, G. (Box 63, Folder 36)
      11th November 1828, Paris. 1l.
    - Joy, G. (Box 63, Folder 37)
      23 June 1829, 1l.
    - Joy, G. (Box 63, Folder 38)
      11th June 1829, 1l.
    - Joy, G. (Box 63, Folder 39)
      11th August 1830, 4 ll.
    - Joy, G. (Box 63, Folder 40)
      30th August 1830. 1l.
    - Joy, G. (Box 63, Folder 41)
      1st September 1830, London. 2 ll.
    - Joy, G. (Box 63, Folder 42)
      7th September 1830, 1l.
    - Kelleher, H. (Box 63, Folder 43)
      1st August 1830, Paris. 1l.
    - Kelleher, H. (Box 63, Folder 44)
      20th September 1830, 1l.
    - King, Charles, 1789-1867 (Box 63, Folder 45)